

Andrew Hercules

Developer. UX Designer. Digital Strategist.

+44 (0)7511 311 454 andrewhercules@gmail.com http://andrewhercules.com

PROFILE -

I am a London-based web developer, user experience (UX) researcher and designer, and digital strategist. And yes, my last name is Hercules, just like the famous Greek hero!

With a diverse and transferable skillset and a range of industry experience, I support and guide organisations that want to transform their operations with technology. Applying a user-centered, co-operative design approach, I research, design, and build solutions that meet the needs of users while streamlining and improving existing organisational practices.

EDUCATION -

MA, Journalism & Media Studies
City University & Aarhus University | 2010

BA, Political Science York University | 2008

Ongoing Training & Development

Ruby on Rails; Prototyping with Axure; UX Research Methods; Google Analytics; Web Accessibility Standards; Adobe CS6

EXPERIENCE -

Developer and UX Researcher/Designer

University of London | Oct 2015 to present

Build institutional repositories for customers in the higher education and research sectors; Engage in user research and design to improve flagship products and services for the higher education sector

Front-End Developer and UX/UI Consultant

Deloitte Digital | Jun 2015 to Oct 2015

Contributed to the development of a single-page, web-based roboadvice demo application for a large, UK-based insurance company; Supported a large-scale digital transformation project at Transport for London (TfL) by engaging in user research sessions and creating design patterns for internal mobile applications

Freelance Digital Consultant

Self-Employed | Jun 2014 to Apr 2015

Worked with a range of clients to understand their existing operations and developed digital strategies that advanced their organisational goals and objectives

Communications Coordinator and Front-End Developer

University of Toronto | Oct 2011 - Sep 2014

Developed and implemented print and digital marketing campaigns for academic and co-curricular programming and initiatives; Provided technical and content support for PHP/HTML/CSS and Drupal websites

SKILLS -

HTML / CSS						0
JavaScript					0	0
Ruby on Rails				0	0	0
User Research						
User Journeys						
Personas						
User Testing		•				
Prototyping						0
Wireframing						0
Strategic Thinking						
Communications						
Web Analytics				0	0	0
Graphic Design				0	0	0